Nicholas G. McMullen

Certified Total Rewards & People Analytics Professional Greater Phoenix Area, Arizona, USA e: nicholasgmcmullen@gmail.com w: nickmcmullen.github.io s: linkedin.com/in/nicholas-mcmullen

Summary

Analytically-inclined, people-oriented HR practitioner with experience supporting executives and front-line teams as a strategic partner. Skilled in analyzing people programs and making sense out of data, rewards design and management, human resources operations, and onboarding. Experienced at implementing, integrating, and managing a variety of HR technology solutions, managing rewards programs, and leading people-people teams.

Employment

Compensation and People Analytics Lead

January 2022 - Present

RStudio PBC Remote. USA

- Establish dedicated compensation consultation function
- Conduct job analysis, evaluation, and benchmarking for all current and new company jobs
- Implement Radford salary survey and benchmarking tool
- Architect suite of automated dashboards using an R-powered shiny app to provide key stakeholders with a high-level overview of employee lifecycle metrics
- Act as lead People Ops stakeholder for building automated data exchange between ATS and HRIS
- Lead automated data exchange setup between HRIS and employee engagement/listening platform
- Build and automated employee lifecycle surveys including a 90-day new hire survey and annual employee engagement survey

People Operations Partner

January 2021 - January 2022

RStudio PBC Remote, USA

- Established company wide job code architecture
- Assisted with talent management initiatives and employee relations matters
- Architected career frameworks for technical staff
- Created and led "manager meetup" development calls
- Conducted 90-day check ins with all new employees
- Managed job analysis, evaluation, and benchmarking process

Senior Specialist, Total Rewards Content

September 2020 - January 2021

WorldatWork Remote, USA

- Authored a complete practice strategy with market research for executive leadership,
- Wrote data taxonomy for Salesforce CRM environment and defined new key workflows
- Advised leadership on marketplace education and certification trends in total rewards

Manager, People Systems and Analytics

January 2020 - September 2020

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Oversaw operation and management of all people-related systems, including HRIS, ATS, compensation, and corporate social responsibility.
- Implemented and integrated new CSR platform with HRIS.
- Managed the calculation and processing of quarterly bonuses for 2500+ site and regional operations employees.
- Acted as HR liaison to the company compensation committee.
- Assisted with M&A activities related to HR data during Greystar/Alliance merger.

Manager, Talent Analytics and Operations

May 2018 - January 2020

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Led configuration and ongoing optimization efforts of iCIMS ATS.
- Built and automated suite of Tableau dashboards for talent acquisition executive team for monthly reporting requirements.
- Automated monthly recruiting fee bill-back process, increasing accuracy of processing to 99% and saving 25 monthly hours of manual reporting and auditing.
- Implemented Salary.com CompAnalyst and conducted market benchmarking for all company jobs.
- Managed centralized recruiting coordinator team of two responsible for administrative and compliance-related onboarding tasks that successfully onboarded 2000+ employees over 20 months across 25 US states.

Learning and Development Intern

June 2017 - August 2017

Alliance Residential Company Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Analyzed a pilot sales training program for impact on closing leases, resulting in full adoption of the program organization-wide.
- Restructured company knowledge bank in Cornerstone OnDemand LMS.
- Converted, redesigned, and published online company training courses from Adobe Captivate format to Articulate Rise 360 in Cornerstone OnDemand LMS.
- Managed pool and HVAC maintenance certification program, including tracking in Cornerstone OnDemand LMS and conducting ongoing compliance reporting.

Education

B.A. magna cum laude, Applied Mathematics and Statistics

August 2014 - May 2018

Macalester College St. Paul, MN, USA

Certifications

Certified Compensation Professional (CCP)

WorldatWork

Expires November 2023

Global Remuneration Professional (GRP)

WorldatWork

Expires November 2023

Professional in Human Resources (PHR)

Human Resources Certification Institute (HRCI)

Tableau Desktop 2019 Certified Associate (expired)

Tableau Software

Expired October 2021

Expires February 2024

Skills

- Base pay design and administration
- Job analysis, documentation, and evaluation
- Incentive compensation program management
- HRIS integration and administration
- ATS implementation, administration
- LMS implementation, administration
- Talent onboarding process development and management
- People program analysis and evaluation
- Data cleaning and manipulation
- Process improvement, design, and automation
- People team management

Software Experience

- R programming
- Shiny app development
- RStudio IDE
- Radford
- BambooHR HRIS
- Greenhouse.io ATS
- Culture Amp
- Salary.com CompAnalyst

- UltiPro HRIS (UKG)
- iCIMS ATS
- Fuse LXP
- Cornerstone OnDemand LMS
- Qualtrics